<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hichem Ben Marzoug</title>
    <description>The professional portfolio and blog of Hichem Ben Marzoug, an IT leadership professional specializing in system mergers, cloud infrastructure, and operational efficiency.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 21:53:47 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 21:53:47 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.10.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Optimizing Google Workspace Operations at Buzzman</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Streamlining Collaboration and Administration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation:&lt;/strong&gt; At Buzzman, an advertising agency with approximately 80-100 users, Google Workspace (then Google Apps for Work) was the core platform for email, document collaboration, and communication (Gmail, Drive, Hangouts)[cite: 136]. While functional, there were opportunities to optimize its administration and ensure best practices were followed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Task:&lt;/strong&gt; My objective was to streamline the management of the Google Workspace instance, improve operational efficiency for user onboarding/offboarding, and ensure the platform was being utilized effectively and securely according to company needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Admin Review:&lt;/strong&gt; Conducted a thorough review of the existing Google Workspace setup, including user accounts, groups, Drive sharing permissions, and security settings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process Refinement:&lt;/strong&gt; Standardized processes for user provisioning, de-provisioning, and group management to ensure consistency and security.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feature Utilization:&lt;/strong&gt; Promoted the effective use of core features like shared Drives (Team Drives), Calendar resources, and Google Meet for efficient collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security Best Practices:&lt;/strong&gt; Implemented or reinforced security best practices, such as encouraging 2-Step Verification adoption and reviewing third-party app access.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support &amp;amp; Troubleshooting:&lt;/strong&gt; Acted as the primary point of contact for Google Workspace related support issues, resolving user queries and technical problems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploration of Automation (Conceptual for Buzzman, implemented later elsewhere):&lt;/strong&gt; While at Buzzman, the scale might not have demanded complex automation, the experience here [cite: 136] laid the groundwork for later leveraging tools like GAM for batch operations [cite: 140, 143, 145, 148] and custom app development for onboarding (as done at Drivy [cite: 137, 138, 139]).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result:&lt;/strong&gt;
The focused management of Google Workspace at Buzzman led to more efficient IT operations, particularly around user lifecycle management. Employees had reliable access to essential collaboration tools, and foundational security practices were maintained, ensuring a stable platform for the agency’s creative work. This hands-on experience with a smaller instance provided valuable insights for managing larger, more complex Google Workspace environments in subsequent roles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buzzman-google-workspace-optimization</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buzzman-google-workspace-optimization</guid>
        
        
        <category>Buzzman</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Case Study: Enhancing Company-Wide Security with 1Password</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is an example of proactive IT management and adaptability, where an immediate team-level need was leveraged to address a larger, more strategic business objective: enhancing the company’s overall security posture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initiative began when the &lt;a href=&quot;https://getaround.tech/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;EPDD (Engineering, Product, Data, and Design) teams&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://getaround.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Drivy&lt;/a&gt; needed a replacement for a credential-sharing tool that was being discontinued. My IT roadmap had already identified the need for a company-wide password manager, so I expanded the project’s scope to meet this larger goal. After a formal RFP process and vendor evaluation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://1password.com/business-security&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;1Password for Teams&lt;/a&gt; was selected as the optimal solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed the full project lifecycle over a three-month period, structured in three main phases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the technical deployment and integration,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a phased user onboarding and training program for over 130 employees across Europe, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the development of comprehensive documentation for long-term sustainability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key success factors included close alignment with stakeholder requirements from the outset and a carefully planned, phased rollout that prioritized the highest-need teams first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project not only met its technical goals but also delivered significant cultural and security-related outcomes. It fostered a company-wide culture of security awareness, with users demonstrating a clear commitment to stronger security practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A notable metric of success was that approximately 65% of employees adopted the tool for personal use, indicating high user satisfaction and trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This initiative successfully established 1Password as a fundamental and valued component of Drivy’s Information System.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/drivy-1password-deployment</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/drivy-1password-deployment</guid>
        
        
        <category>Drivy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>EU HQ Relocation to Paris</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Establishing the New Los Angeles Tech Hub&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation:&lt;/strong&gt; Jellysmack, a company focused on empowering online content creators[cite: 220], decided to establish a new USA headquarters in Los Angeles, specifically at the Pacific Design Center[cite: 133]. As IT Director, I joined during a period of company restructuring[cite: 222].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Task:&lt;/strong&gt; I was responsible for supervising all IT aspects of this significant office relocation and setup[cite: 133]. This included designing the IT infrastructure for the new space, managing vendors, ensuring connectivity, and coordinating the technology needs for the employees moving into the new HQ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action:&lt;/strong&gt;
My responsibilities encompassed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure Design &amp;amp; Planning:&lt;/strong&gt; Collaborated with facilities and architects to plan network cabling, server room requirements (if any, or cloud-first approach), Wi-Fi coverage, and AV setups for meeting rooms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendor Management:&lt;/strong&gt; Sourced and managed vendors for internet service provision, network hardware installation, and AV equipment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Procurement &amp;amp; Asset Management:&lt;/strong&gt; Oversaw the procurement of new IT equipment (laptops, monitors, peripherals) as needed and managed the inventory for the new location.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network &amp;amp; Systems Setup:&lt;/strong&gt; Configured and deployed network infrastructure (routers, switches, firewalls, access points) and ensured seamless integration with existing Jellysmack corporate systems and security protocols.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-site Support &amp;amp; Go-Live:&lt;/strong&gt; Coordinated with any local IT support (even if it was a new hire like Taurean mentioned in another context [cite: 221, 224]) to manage the final setup and provide on-site support during the initial move-in phase, ensuring a smooth transition for employees.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Budget Oversight:&lt;/strong&gt; Managed the IT budget allocated for the relocation project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result:&lt;/strong&gt;
The new Jellysmack USA HQ in Los Angeles was successfully launched from an IT perspective, providing a robust and modern technological environment for employees. The infrastructure was designed to support current needs and future growth, ensuring reliable connectivity and access to all necessary corporate resources from day one. This project was crucial in establishing a key operational hub for the company in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jellysmack-usa-hq-relocation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jellysmack-usa-hq-relocation</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jellysmack</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Implementing AWS Workspaces for Specialized Needs at Alan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Built a lightweight Virtual Desktop infrastructure, hosted on AWS.
The goal was to provide for Windows systems, in a full-macOS ecosystem, for users in need of specific Windows-only software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/alan-virtual-desktop-infrastructure</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/alan-virtual-desktop-infrastructure</guid>
        
        
        <category>Alan</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Streamlining IT Asset Management at Qonto with Reftab</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enhancing IT Asset Visibility and Control&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Situation:&lt;/strong&gt; As Qonto, a company in the banking industry[cite: 146], experienced rapid growth, managing the expanding inventory of IT assets (laptops, mobile devices, peripherals) became increasingly complex. A robust and centralized asset management system was needed for tracking, maintenance, and compliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Task:&lt;/strong&gt; The goal was to implement an IT inventory tool to improve asset tracking, lifecycle management, and provide accurate data for financial reporting and security audits. Reftab was identified as the tool to be used. [cite: 152]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Needs Assessment:&lt;/strong&gt; Worked with IT, Finance, and Security teams to define the requirements for the asset management system, including data points to track, reporting needs, and integration capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reftab Configuration:&lt;/strong&gt; Spearheaded the configuration and customization of the Reftab platform to align with Qonto’s specific asset types, locations, and workflows.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Migration:&lt;/strong&gt; Oversaw the process of populating Reftab with existing asset data, ensuring accuracy and completeness. This may have involved manual entry, spreadsheet imports, or integration with other systems if possible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process Integration:&lt;/strong&gt; Integrated Reftab into IT operational processes, including employee onboarding (asset assignment), offboarding (asset retrieval), repairs, and disposal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Training:&lt;/strong&gt; Trained the IT team on using Reftab for daily asset management tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reporting Setup:&lt;/strong&gt; Established reporting mechanisms within Reftab to provide insights into asset distribution, aging, and status for compliance and financial purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result:&lt;/strong&gt;
The implementation of Reftab provided Qonto with a centralized and accurate IT asset inventory. This led to improved efficiency in tracking and managing assets, better control over the asset lifecycle, reduced risk of loss or theft, and streamlined processes for audits and financial reporting. It also supported the high-security requirements of a banking industry company by ensuring all IT assets were accounted for. [cite: 146, 152]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/qonto-reftab-inventory</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/qonto-reftab-inventory</guid>
        
        
        <category>Qonto</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paving the Road to ISO 27001: A TISAX Compliance Deep Dive</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My approach to IT has always been grounded in the robust frameworks that govern enterprise-level security and operations. I’ve consistently drawn inspiration from standards like NIST to build processes that are not just efficient, but also secure and auditable. In 2020, this governance-first mindset became critical when Getaround embarked on the path to TISAX compliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-strategic-imperative-aligning-with-automotive-industry-standards&quot;&gt;The Strategic Imperative: Aligning with Automotive Industry Standards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TISAX (Trusted Information Security Assessment Exchange) is the gold standard for information security in the automotive industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Getaround, preparing for the TISAX assessment was a strategic business imperative required to strengthen partnerships and operate with the highest level of trust within this ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a key IT stakeholder, my role was to architect and drive the implementation of the core policies and controls necessary to meet these rigorous standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I collaborated closely with a dedicated cross-functional team, our Legal Counsel, and a third-party audit partner to build a comprehensive information security framework from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;building-a-framework-of-governance-risk-and-compliance-grc&quot;&gt;Building a Framework of Governance, Risk, and Compliance (GRC)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our work began with a comprehensive gap analysis, measuring our existing IT systems against the stringent TISAX assessment criteria, which are heavily influenced by the ISO 27001 framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My leadership was central to authoring, sponsoring, and implementing a suite of policies that would serve as the foundation of our new GRC framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the official &lt;strong&gt;Sponsor&lt;/strong&gt; for IT topics, I took ultimate ownership of several core policies, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access Management Policy:&lt;/strong&gt; Establishing a “least-privilege” access model based on NIST guidelines to define and verify user access to all critical systems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Disk Encryption Policy:&lt;/strong&gt; Mandating and outlining the processes for encrypting all company devices to protect data at rest, a fundamental security control.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network Management Policy:&lt;/strong&gt; Defining secure configuration standards for all network equipment to protect our data from unauthorized access and ensure network integrity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IT Asset Management Policy:&lt;/strong&gt; Creating a formal lifecycle for all physical IT assets—from planning and acquisition to secure disposal—based on ISO standards and NIST best practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond sponsoring these documents, I provided critical stewardship for other essential policies, including those for Business Continuity Planning, Data Backups, and the Responsible Use of IT Systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-outcome-a-foundational-step-towards-iso-27001-certification&quot;&gt;The Outcome: A Foundational Step Towards ISO 27001 Certification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through this structured and policy-driven approach, we successfully established a mature, auditable information security program built on internationally recognized standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While our initial focus was TISAX, the comprehensive GRC framework, policies, and controls we developed were instrumental in paving the way for the company’s future success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The foundational work performed by our team directly enabled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20240820729492/en/Getaround-Successfully-Secures-ISO-27001-Certification-Reinforces-Leadership-in-Carsharing-Connected-Car-Space&quot;&gt;Getaround to achieve &lt;/a&gt;the prestigious &lt;strong&gt;ISO 27001 certification&lt;/strong&gt; a few years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was a testament to the power of proactive governance. By treating compliance not as a final destination but as a framework for operational excellence, we fundamentally strengthened the company’s security posture and built the necessary foundation for future security achievements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It solidified my belief that a rigorous, policy-driven approach is the most effective way to manage risk and build trust in any regulated industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/getaround-tisax-compliance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/getaround-tisax-compliance</guid>
        
        
        <category>Getaround</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Case Study: Orchestrating the Drivy-Getaround Google Workspace Merger</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2019, following the acquisition of Drivy by its US competitor Getaround, I was faced with the most defining project of my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the sole IT Manager for Drivy in Europe, and with Getaround having no dedicated IT staff at the time, the responsibility for the initial, critical phase of the merger (the integration of our core IT systems- fell on my shoulders. The very first, and most foundational, piece of this puzzle was merging our two distinct Google Workspace environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-strategic-challenge-more-than-just-a-data-migration&quot;&gt;The Strategic Challenge: More Than Just a Data Migration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective was technically complex but strategically vital: migrate all 200+ Drivy user accounts—including every email, calendar event, and Drive file—into the larger, 1100-user Getaround instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t just a data transfer; it was about laying the technical groundwork for unifying two distinct company cultures across continents. The project timeline was aggressive, driven by pressing marketing and business objectives that required a swift and seamless integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the scale and tight deadlines, I made the strategic decision to partner with a third-party specialist, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gcloud.devoteam.com/&quot;&gt;Devoteam G Cloud&lt;/a&gt;, to assist with the raw data migration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my role was to be the project’s chief architect and conductor, orchestrating every facet of the merger from planning and vendor management to technical execution and change management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-project-lifecycle-a-blend-of-technical-mastery-and-strategic-oversight&quot;&gt;The Project Lifecycle: A Blend of Technical Mastery and Strategic Oversight&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I designed and managed a multi-phased project plan that prioritized risk mitigation and minimal user disruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Discovery, Planning, and Vendor Management:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project began with a meticulous audit of both Google Workspace environments. 
On the Drivy side, we had a primary domain with five aliases and critical integrations with CRMs like Zendesk. The Getaround side was a much larger, global instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I established a clear project governance structure, set up technical workshops, and defined the migration strategy. This foundational work formed the basis of the RFP for our third-party partner and ensured a smooth collaboration with Devoteam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Technical Execution &amp;amp; The Role of GAM:&lt;/strong&gt;
While our partner handled the “migration factory” setup, my hands-on technical expertise was crucial for managing the user-side operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I extensively used &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GAM-team/GAM&quot;&gt;GAM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a command-line tool, to perform critical batch operations that were outside the scope of the migration tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This included creating and mapping user accounts, managing groups with specific parameters, and executing the complex user renaming process during the final cutover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My proficiency with GAM was instrumental in managing the ~200 Drivy accounts and integrating them into the larger ~1100 user Getaround environment efficiently and without error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Phased Migration &amp;amp; Change Management:&lt;/strong&gt;
To minimize risk, we executed the migration in carefully planned stages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-Migration:&lt;/strong&gt; We first migrated all “cold” data older than 60 days to move the bulk of information without impacting active work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delta Migration:&lt;/strong&gt; Subsequent passes migrated more recent data, which I scheduled after work hours to avoid disruption.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cutover:&lt;/strong&gt; The final migration and switchover were meticulously planned for the last weekend of August, a period of lower activity that would minimize business impact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication was paramount. I developed a multi-channel communication plan using a mix of &lt;strong&gt;asynchronous&lt;/strong&gt; (Slack, email, a dedicated Google Sites wiki for all information) and &lt;strong&gt;synchronous&lt;/strong&gt; (weekly stand-ups, company-wide All-Hands meetings) methods to keep every stakeholder informed and to prepare users for the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-outcome-a-999-success-rate-and-a-unified-company&quot;&gt;The Outcome: A 99.9% Success Rate and a Unified Company&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project was completed on schedule and achieved a &lt;strong&gt;99.90% success rate&lt;/strong&gt; in data migration. The only notable issue involved a handful of legacy Google Sites V1 pages that were incompatible with the migration tools. Even then, I was able to manually rebuild and recover approximately 60% of this content from archives and backups, ensuring minimal data loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the technical success, the true result was cultural. The unified Google Workspace instance became a key milestone in the merger. It broke down geographical barriers, enabled seamless cross-continental collaboration from day one, and was a powerful symbol of our new, integrated company identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was a testament to the power of combining deep technical knowledge with strategic project management to navigate one of the most critical phases of a corporate acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/case-study-it-merger-drivy-getaround</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/case-study-it-merger-drivy-getaround</guid>
        
        
        <category>Drivy</category>
        
        <category>Getaround</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Case Study: IT Crisis Management &amp; Infrastructure Recovery at Drivy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In IT leadership, you plan for every contingency, but true capability is often demonstrated when the unexpected happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February 2018, while at Drivy, we faced a significant crisis: &lt;strong&gt;a fire broke out&lt;/strong&gt; on a lower floor of our office building, sending smoke and soot through the utility shafts and compromising critical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-challenge-from-crisis-discovery-to-business-continuity&quot;&gt;The Challenge: From Crisis Discovery to Business Continuity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fire started on a Saturday while the building was empty, but the business impact was immediate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With firefighters blocking all access to the building, our entire on-site network infrastructure was down and inaccessible. The fire had impacted the building’s technical closets, rendering key components of our network inoperable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My primary objective was clear: ensure a fully operational and stable network environment to allow over 100 employees to return to work seamlessly as soon as the building was cleared by the authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the CEO’s full trust and a &lt;em&gt;carte blanche&lt;/em&gt; to resolve the situation, I immediately partnered with the Office Manager to execute a rapid recovery plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-approach-a-methodical-response-under-pressure&quot;&gt;My Approach: A Methodical Response Under Pressure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My immediate priority was to conduct a thorough and systematic damage assessment. While our teams were temporarily relocated to coworking spaces, I initiated a multi-point inspection:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;External Connectivity (WAN):&lt;/strong&gt; I visually inspected the building’s technical rooms and liaised directly with our Internet Service Provider to confirm the integrity of our primary fiber optic link.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internal Infrastructure:&lt;/strong&gt; I meticulously tested all internal hardware, including switches and access points. This process quickly isolated the point of failure: our main network router was inoperable due to electric damage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a precise diagnosis, I moved from assessment to resolution. The timeline was extremely tight. Leveraging my network of trusted vendors, I negotiated the expedited acquisition of a new router that met both our technical requirements and budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key technical challenge was that the new router was from a different manufacturer, requiring me to quickly adapt and configure a new system to match our existing network architecture; a task that demanded both technical knowledge and adaptability under pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-outcome-a-seamless-return-and-a-stronger-foundation&quot;&gt;The Outcome: A Seamless Return and a Stronger Foundation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a direct result of this swift and methodical approach, the new network infrastructure was fully deployed, configured, and tested before the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The return to the office was smooth, with zero IT-related disruptions for our employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This incident served as a powerful real-world stress test of my ability to manage crises, make critical decisions under pressure, and combine technical skills with strategic vendor management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, the lessons learned and the architecture I designed during this recovery process became an invaluable blueprint for the more complex network infrastructure I would later deploy for the company’s new headquarters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a clear demonstration that effective IT leadership isn’t just about maintaining systems, but about ensuring business resilience in the face of any challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/case-study-it-crisis-management-drivy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/case-study-it-crisis-management-drivy</guid>
        
        
        <category>Drivy</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
